Lynn Z. Bloom Collection Relating to Benjamin Spock
Lynn Z. Bloom Collection Relating to Benjamin Spock
- Recordings, audio
  - College and Post-College Life; Medical School and Early Practice; Mail, 21-30 Mar 1967; bloom_spock_036; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A 3/21/67: Frontier College; Volunteer camp counselor; N.E. Crip. Children’s Home; Summer tutoring job; Yale Reunions; Yale Loyalties (in general); Southampton job; Frontier College; Med. school; Univ. stastics [sic] re. peace; W.R.U. Family Clinic; New England / Side 1B 3/21/67: Rochester, Minn.; Hosting parties; Jane; Miscellaneous remarks, 1963 prob, mail; 1962 Duell, S. & P. mail / Side 2A: Not Transcribed - 3/30/67; 1963 Prob. mail / Side 2B 3/30/67: Misc., B and C; Med. School; Psych. residency; Psychoanalysis; Private Ped. Practice; Summer plays - Adirondacks; Private practice; Psychoanalysis Training; Peds. vs. psychiatry; Rochester, Minn.
  - Meeting Mrs. Spock, Early Career; Life Before Fame, bloom_spock_037; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A - Mrs. Spock: Courtship; Engagement; Honeymoon; NY - 1927; Dr. S. - radio address / Side 2A - Mrs. Spock: NY - 1927; Europe; Mike’s birth; Motherhood; NY - 1931; Liberalism; NY; Ben’s Family; Mike as a child; John; Early Politics; John - now; Romances; TV show; NY - 1943; B and CC; Navy; John’s birth; Pregnancies / Side 2B - Mrs. Spock: Navy; B and CC; Navy; Job Offers; Rochester, Minn.; John’s Celiac Disease; Rochester, Cleveland; Rochester, Pittsburgh; Cleveland; New Yacht; Finances; RedBook; Fame
  - Interviews: Jane Spock, family and friends, Boudin, 23 Oct 1968; bloom_spock_038; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Jane Spock 10/23/68 1A: Misc. / 2A: family and friends / 1B: family and friends / 2B: Boudin - 1/4 used
  - Mrs. Spock: family life and Dr. Spock as husband and father, bloom_spock_039; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Side 1A Mrs. Spock: Dr. S.’s criticalness; Mike’s beard; Family appearance; NY Apt in 1940; Future travel plans; Annual earnings; Dr. S. as a Father; John; Dr. S. with reporters; 1/2 B and CC by her; Differences between John and Mike; Dr. S. as a husband; joining SANE; Vanity; many moves; TV Show; Retirement / Side 1B Mrs. Spock: Dr. S. as a father; Publicity; Dr. S.’s mother + father; Dr. S.’s siblings; Sailing; courting danger; grandchildren; M’s jealousy of John; Mike and John; Marriage; Dr. S. as a Father / Side 2A Mrs. Spock: Marriage; Dr. Spock: Dr. S. as a father, Andover, Yale, Rebelliousness, Yale, Mike and John, Mike’s schooling, John’s schooling, American education, Caroline Zachery, Maragaret Mead / Side 2B: unsuccessful as therapist; B+CC: confidence in humanity; B and CC; SANE Wrangle; Files
  - Mrs. Spock on Dr. Spock’s later career; various files, 08 May 1967; bloom_spock_040; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Side 1A Mrs. Spock 5/8/67: Dr. S’s Health; Dr. S.’s personality; Retirement; Engagement; Reporters; Life in the public eye; SANE; marriage; entertaining; friendships; W.R.U.; friendships / Side 1B - Mrs. Spock: friendships; private practice; private life; marriage - early years; private life; marriage / Side 2A: private life; private practice; private life; wedding; mother-in-law; 1965-66 memorabilia file / 2B - Files: sponsorships (committed); miscellaneous comments; memorabilia - awards; memorabilia - Pres. ILLia
  - Mrs. Spock: Photos and Reminiscences, bloom_spock_041; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Side 1A - Mrs Spock 1966: Photos; Rowing; Photos; Mrs. S. against Prohibition; Pittsburgh; Political opinion differences; Photos / Side 1B: A.D.A.; Photos; Bossie Quigg; Photos; Santa Claus; Photos; Health; White House Dinner / Side 2A: White House Article; Scientists, Engineers & Physicians for LBJ; Photos
  - Lynn B. on radio, Mrs. Spock, Various files, Mar 1967; bloom_spock_042; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Side 1A: Lynn B on radio via Faulkner / Side 1B - Mrs. Spock 1962: Photos; Honorary Degree; Pocket Chain; Marriage; Photos; Drafting Table; Dr. S.’s Appearance; Photos / Side 2A: Photos; John’s Schooling; Photos; Awards; Furniture; Children; 1967 Files; LB on Spock 3/67 / Side 2B: 1962 - Problem Mail; SANE / 1947 - Insurance; B and CC; Book Correspondence
  - Mike Spock, 11 Aug 1967; bloom_spock_043; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    2A: Mike Spock Aug. 11, 1967; 2B: Mike Spock, Aug. 11, 1967
  - Interviews: Robert Stein, Charles Duell, Caldwell Esseltyn, 15 Aug 1968; bloom_spock_044; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1A: Robert Stein, Aug. 15, 1968 / 2A: Charles Duell (?), Stein / 1B: Caldwell Esseltyn, M.D., Aug. 15, 1968 / 2B: Chas. Duell; Stein?
  - Sue Streeter and Paul White, 22 Mar 1968; bloom_spock_045; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1A: Sue Streeter and Paul White, March 22, 1968 / 1B: Sue Streeter and Paul White, March 22, 1968
  - Lecture on violence in the family; Various files, 19 Apr 1967; bloom_spock_046; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1A: Lecture on violence in the family - 4/19/67 / 1B: Violence in the family - first half; Office files S-T; routine stuff and early '67 letters / 2A: Office files V-Z; 1966 memorabilia / 2B: memorabilia files; 1966; Navy file
  - Various files; Reminiscences of Western Reserve University and early career, bloom_spock_047; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1A: 1967 Misc. Jan.-June; 1962 on - Appts and Awards; 1967 - Speaking Regrets, Boats, Book File ("Man"), Contributions, Houghton Mifflin, Job Offers, Miscellaneous, Organization Regrets, Peace Groups / 1B: 1967 - Peace Groups, Personal Mail, Pocket Books, Problem Mail; 1958 on - Recommendation Letters; 1967 - Record (Cardmon), Redbook / 2A: WRU - Child Research Project, B and CC, Adolescence, Friday Pediatric Lectures, Criticalness, Dancing Academy (1930s), Social Friends, Conscience-Driven, Health, Boating, Brief Summary of Previous Jobs, Week of May 15-22, Capt. Levy, Switch from LHJ to Redbook / 2B: Capt. Levy; Univ. of Pitts.; W.R.U.; 1967 Misc, and Memorabilia Files
  - Office files "Integration - Medical Economies"; "M - Pediatrics", 1980-01-29; bloom_spock_048; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1-29-80: 1A: Talks refused '63; Office Files ("M - Pediatrics") / 1B: Office files Ped 4 - / 2A: about 5 min. not recorded at beg.; rest - Dr. S - office files "Integration - Medical Economies."